♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ next Sunday, A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy
named Joel ♪
♪ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked
at gizmonic institute ♪
♪ just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ he did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ but his bosses
didn'’t like him ♪
♪ so they shot him
into space ♪
♪♪
♪ we'’ll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ the worst we can find
la la la ♪
♪ he'’ll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ then we'’ll monitor his mind
la la la ♪
♪ now keep in mind
Joel can'’t control ♪
♪ where the movies begin or end
la la la ♪
♪ because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ to make his robot friends ♪
Robot roll call:
Cambot,
- gypsy...
- Hi, girls.
- ... Tom servo...
- What a cool guy.
- ... crow!
- What a wisecracker.
♪ If you'’re wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ and other science facts
la la la ♪
♪ then repeat to yourself
it'’s just a show ♪
♪ I should really
just relax ♪
♪ for mystery science theater ♪
♪ 3000 ♪♪
They promised me students,
but all I got were monkeys.
Monkeys!
So I took off my wetsuit,
dropped that hedge clipper,
and walked out of the zoo
forever!
Well, you'’ve created
quite a little world
for yourself, Larry.
Hey, tell me about
when you went mad now.
Well, it was the ice capades,
and I was pop-riveting
my kneecaps
to Peggy Fleming'’s
zamboni.
Or maybe it was '’56,
sun valley.
I was found behind
the soft-serve machine
drooling over a picture
of dick button.
Or perhaps Oslo, when I was
found drunk and woozy,
scratching the name
"toller Cranston"
into my upper thigh
with a nail.
You see, when i--
- is that when you went mad?
- No, that'’s when I became
a scientist.
Oh... oh!
Speaking of science,
it'’s time to call Joel.
We have to start
the experiment.
The movie'’s great
this week.
Oh, yes, yes.
Come in, Joel,
you fancy-pantsy
Nancy boy.
Hey, sirs, i'’m ready for
this week'’s invention exchange.
Bring it in a little bit,
cambot.
This is a special purse
I developed
for women who are
sick and tired
of the constant threat
of getting their purse snatched.
See how it looks like
an ordinary handbag.
When street thugs open it,
voila!
Hell in a handbag.
Nice use of pain,
joelmeister.
Now here'’s ours.
As you know,
toy manufacturers are always
making their toys
too safe.
And what children want
is realism.
And danger!
That'’s why we created
the acetylene-powered
thunder lizard.
Yes, it'’s a role-playing game,
and it comes complete
with these costume glasses.
Just set up
your field of play,
then reach out
and torch someone.
[Laughing]
- I like it!
Look at him go!
Heh heh heh.
Oh, that'’s gotta hurt.
Wow, that'’s really sick
and twisted.
[Both]
Thank you.
Now here'’s something that'’ll
really rub you wrong.
Yes, it'’s one
of our favorites.
It'’s called "mad monster."
Oh, it'’s got a neat
little laboratory
tucked behind a bookcase,
and a couch you can
strap victims to!
Yes, and the screen is alive
with crepe hair and spirit gum.
Oh, oh, and we have
the second installment
of "rocket men on the moon."
Oh... ecch!
Yes, this one is called
"the molten terror."
[Larry laughing
fiendishly]
[Alarm buzzer blaring]
Oh, movie sign!
[Industrial clanks
and thunks]
♪♪
I know, I gotta get wheels
for you, sweet Tom.
Those scientists are
really dorks.
It'’s pumpkin boy again.
"Radar men from the moon."
Hey, it stars the same people
as last week.
Aw, it'’s just "featuring"
the same people as last week.
Featuring, sorry.
These are the extras.
They'’ll probably get killed.
Dale Van sickel never made
a bad film.
He never made a real film.
♪♪
Consolidated film industries.
Franklin ad--
oh.
We can only dream.
Chapter two:
"Molten terror"!
Ooh, isn'’t terror bad enough
without being molten?
"Commando Cody fights
the moon men in an effort
"to escape retik,
who plans to disintegrate him
with a ray pistol."
Oh, then they'’re gonna
work things out.
Hey, Joel, didn'’t we
see this last time?
Yeah, they'’re just
recapping what happened.
Well, he blew up the same.
But he continued to fight
with the sock man.
Willard Scott then reloaded
his cheese pistol.
Isn'’t that Marty feldman?
Guns by vidal sassoon.
This is where
we came in, you guys.
Oh, if they would have
shown him
diving out of the way
last time,
I wouldn'’t have spent the week
worrying about him.
Nice punch.
He walked right into it.
Ugh.
Hmm, lobby, first floor.
Tobacconist,
newspapers.
I'’m outside.
Let'’s see,
I stand in this corner,
little tweak of the nipples,
and i'’m outta here.
Oh-- oh, no!
Oh...
- Oh...
- Amazing.
You'’ll believe
a man can fly.
Meanwhile,
back at mesa verde.
That'’s gotta be hard
on the arches,
I Don'’t care where
you'’re from.
Oh, I think those fell
a long time ago.
I'’ll be in my trailer.
Hope there'’s some
deli food left.
And no brown M&M'’s
this time.
[Sputtering hiss]
Oh, how rude!
So retik plans
to invade the earth
with the zombies
from the moon
as soon as the saboteurs
he already has there
finish softening up
our defenses.
Do you think he'’ll be able
to do it?
I'’m afraid he might.
I Don'’t know how many men
or rocket ships he has,
but his atomic weapons
are so far ahead
of anything we have, he wouldn'’t
need a very big army.
What did you find out
about the ray guns?
Ron and Nancy?
They use an element called
lumarium instead of uranium
as the base for their
atomic reactions.
And they take an hour
to load.
They currently can control
the reactions
so they will work either
as a disintegrating ray
or as an explosion,
like our atomic bomb.
Well, if their weapons are
that powerful,
it would be impossible for our
people to attack them here.
Stop whining.
She'’s got a real hairy nape.
Apparently,
they let us land because
they weren'’t afraid
of a single ship,
but they would undoubtedly
blast it at an invading fleet.
Then hadn'’t we better
go back right away
and warn our people?
Our orders were to find out
if the attacks
were coming from here.
And if so, to try
to figure out
some way to stop them.
Those are large orders.
All we have is
a light machine gun
and some hand grenades.
They wouldn'’t do much
to that walled city.
No, but there was one
of they ray guns
in retik'’s laboratory.
If I could get hold
of that,
it would be easy
to blast open
their pressurized buildings and
really put them out of business.
Then we'’ll have a sale.
That may not be too tough.
We brought some nitrous oxide
with us, didn'’t we?
Yes, there'’s a small tank
of it.
Why did we bring that,
anyway?
Who'’s gonna be first.
They got it from Dennis hopper,
I think.
I'’ll find the air intake that
leads to retik'’s laboratory
and turn the gas
into it.
That ought to put them
to sleep long enough
to let me get away
with the ray gun.
If it'’s like the gun
you found on earth,
it'’ll be too heavy to carry,
let alone fly with.
That'’s right, but the tripod
isn'’t important.
I'’ll dismantle the gun
from the tripod.
I think I can handle
the gun all right.
- He'’s feeling pretty good.
- It'’ll be quite a load.
I better get a helmet
and go with you.
Hank and Joan can stay here
and guard the ship.
Okay. I may need some help
at that.
Dibs on the rocket pack!
I got it-- no, my turn.
Oh, shoot.
Oh, so they'’re both
walking now.
They'’re "walking on the moon."
You better not come
any closer.
I'’ll fly on in
and get the gun.
I'’ll manage to lug it back
this far myself.
With the whole town
chasing you?
Good thing they move
so we know who'’s talking.
I Don'’t think they can get
around out side very well.
How come they got
Groucho Marx moustaches
on their helmets?
Nipple tweak,
and i'’m off.
This is getting easy.
I love it
when he does that.
That'’s so cool.
He'’s gonna fly right into
the commercial, I think.
Hey, Diana Ross is playing
at Caesar'’s palace.
And speaking
of Diana Ross...
That looks just like the roof
of my old grade school.
Let'’s see, just hook up
that nitrous oxide
to the air-intake shaft,
then we can do some serious
dental work in there.
What'’s he gonna do, anyway,
take out their fillings
and serve them
really cold drinks?
Maybe it'’s really helium,
and they'’ll sound
like the munchkins.
Let'’s see, what'’s
a four-letter word
that means "lunar"?
Planet?
No, too many letters.
[Gas hissing]
There he goes!
Woozy. No,
that doesn'’t fit either.
Hookah... hookah.
Something'’s wrong
with the ventilating system.
- Get the oxygen.
- No, it'’s my nap time.
It'’s not that hard
of a job.
Man, they'’re really
overacting in this thing.
Nice swoon.
It'’s not that heavy.
[Door creaks]
Oh, you'’d think in the future
on the moon
they'’d at least
get rid of the creaks.
Yeah.
Faker, faker!
You'’re dead.
Hey, either of you guys got
a 9/16 wrench?
I'’ll just use
this church key here.
Smell my fingers.
You'’re breathing
for two now.
- Buddy breathing.
- That'’s better, huh?
Oh, great, hit him in the face
and hurt your hand.
Dumb-o.
Just give him
a headbutt.
Give him a headbutt,
he'’s just wearing spandex
on his head.
That'’s for Bryant gumble!
That'’s for gene shalit.
And that'’s for dressing up
like Carmen Miranda!
God, that was dumb!
Those are all Bob mackie
creations, aren'’t they?
Someone'’s gonna snag
their jammies
on something sharp,
I can tell.
Earth chair!
Harelip!
See if they bust a vase.
I'’ve never seen so many
lava lamps in my life.
Hope he remembers
what level he parked on.
I'’m in the moon man lot.
Maybe they won'’t notice me
carrying this.
It I act really
nonchalant...
Guards!
The earthman has escaped
with the ray gun.
Send a car out
to search for him!
And Don'’t forget
the cheese.
It'’s a moon car.
And it'’s filled
with evil michelin men.
What a goofy-looking
vehicle.
They better hurry.
They gotta get that car back
to the amusement park.
It'’s a e-ticket ride,
you know.
It sure is heavy.
- Is anybody after you?
- Not yet.
Give me a hand with this.
We'’ve got to move fast.
Is it just me, or do those guys
look like the crash dummies?
"You could learn a lot
from a dummy.
Buckle up."
He must have come
this way.
He couldn'’t have got by
the guards
at the canyon bridge.
No, and he won'’t move
very fast carrying that gun.
Those fins really
keep it stable.
I didn'’t know they had
plywood on the moon.
There they are.
Give them a blast.
Hey, that thing'’s
really gonna come in handy
when Alan Shepard
gets to the moon.
It'’s gonna make
a swell golf cart.
Let'’s try to keep going.
Maybe we can dodge around
those rocks and lose '’em.
Maybe you could use the gun.
You know, the big one
that blows up things...
Like moon cars, perhaps?
I wonder if they know
how stupid they look right now.
They'’re still after us.
Let'’s go.
Give him the hershey'’s
head kiss of death.
Kind of looks like
an electric razor.
Even our name says
merry Christmas.
That looks like a cave.
Let'’s get in there.
Good.
It'’s a moon mirage...
Dolt.
It died.
Those old two-cycles,
you know.
We can'’t follow them
in there.
Set the ray gun
at constant heat.
Oh, constance heat!
I love her films!
[Ray gun activating loudly]
You know,
that constant-heat ray
sounds a lot like
a Chevy horn.
This must be the molten terror
of the title.
They'’re turning that mountain
into Taffy.
I think they may turn
our heroes into Taffy soon.
It'’s a big rock candy
mountain.
Snot canyon!
[Ray gun blaring]
What'’s that?
It'’s the land of dairy queen,
and a river of chocolate'’s
coming right for you.
- Never mind the gun!
- Isn'’t that lava?
Well, i'’ll guess
they'’ll be cooked,
but their hands
will be clean.
Pumice action.
What would you do now,
crow?
- I'’d, uh, panic.
- Panic?
Tom?
- Oh, same, no question.
There'’s gotta be a way out.
Here it comes!
Whoa.
This must be what it'’s like
to be in the stomach
of someone drinking
a malt.
- What do you think?
- Look out.
Blow on it.
I think we gotta
get out of here, you guys.
- What a sticky mess.
- It'’s almost time to go.
You coming?
Looks like the floor
of a movie theater.
[Industrial clanks
and thunks]
♪ Macho macho bot ♪
♪ i'’ve got to be
a macho-- ♪
Hey, excuse me, miss.
Hey.
I'’ve never noticed you
on the ship before.
I'’m Tom servo,
man about satellite.
You know, I know
I look small and all,
but i'’m really built
like a cuisinart.
At least,
that'’s what they tell me.
You know, you'’re
kinda quiet.
I like that in a woman,
really.
You know, too many
of the gals I know
just like to rub
exotic oils on me
and fan me, you know.
It'’s okay,
if you know what I mean.
Well, maybe you Don'’t.
I Don'’t know.
I need a change, though.
I need a woman
more my speed,
and I noticed you have
11 of '’em.
Oh, did I offend you.
I'’m sorry.
I see you'’re blushing.
No, that'’s tomato juice.
I love a woman
with juice in their head.
It'’s really a turn-on
to me,
my little scientific
calculator.
[Chuckles]
Ever gotten a wild hair
and just filled your head
with guacamole
just for the hell of it?
I'’m the kind of robot who likes
to throw caution to the wind,
if you know what I mean.
And if you do,
please tell me.
[Laughs]
Hey, I see you'’ve still got
a power cord.
I like a woman with
a healthy power source.
I really do.
You know, i'’m coming on
a bit strong, I know,
and i'’m sorry,
but I love your lines.
God, you'’ve got
classic features.
Crush, grate, chop, whip.
Baby, you'’ve got it all!
[Blender whirring]
Wha-- oh, and a lovely
singing voice, too.
Oh, you do have it all.
Joel, i'’m in lov--
Joel? Joel!
Joel--
that'’s it,
the gauntlet'’s been thrown!
Nobody drinks from my gal!
Let'’s go, come on!
What are you talking about, Tom?
My gal... i'’m in love,
and you'’re drinking from her!
- Let'’s go!
- Tom... Tom, it'’s a blender.
- Wha--
- it'’s a blender.
- Oh, blender.
I knew that.
♪ Macho macho bot
i'’ve got to be ♪
Excuse me, miss,
i'’ve noticed you--
oh, excuse me,
Mr. Coffee.
♪♪
- All right...
- Okay...
There you go.
[Sighs]
Okay.
Gotta look at '’em
on an angle.
Uh, nope.
This is it over here.
- That'’s better.
- They'’re so hard to read.
Left, right.
Hmm.
They should have gotten
the guy out of the light
before they shot this.
- Yeah.
- It'’s the cameraman.
You should be at more
of an angle, crow.
- Switch.
- Oh, that helps.
No, it'’s the same.
Now straight.
Okay.
[Howling]
Kitty!
They must have some sort
of leash law there.
Oh, they do.
Pretty extreme.
Oh, he'’s got a Thorn
in his paw.
I Don'’t think that'’s a Thorn.
I think it'’s an I.V.
Yeah.
Oh, he'’s giving plasma.
Must be down on his luck.
Poor dog.
Acme coyote transfuser.
Now for the thorough
examination.
[Chuckles]
Just relax.
Hey, it'’s bill Bixby
as Lou ferrigno.
[Howling]
Yes, I know, you'’d like
to join your brothers outside
and howl at the moon.
But you'’re serving
a much better purpose.
Yes, you'’re serving science
through me.
[Howling]
And he'’s making
union scale.
Oh, he'’ll soon have him
housebroken.
And it will be painful.
I could have had a v8.
You know, he'’s very protective
about the secret recipe
of his sun tea.
It'’s a bit of the hair
of the dog--
how does that go, Joel?
Hair of the dog
that bit you.
Yeah.
Let'’s see,
three parts gin,
one part vermouth.
I like mine very dry.
Hair designs
by shemp Howard.
He'’s got an itch.
[Groans]
Are you quite comfortable,
Petro?
Sure, doctor.
Just because his circulation'’s
cut off
at his chest, hands,
and waist...
I have no reason
to be afraid.
That'’s right, Petro, you have
nothing to be afraid of.
Nothing at all.
[Wolf howling]
This is gonna hurt the dog
a lot more
than it'’s gonna hurt me.
[Howling]
There, did that hurt?
No, that was just
like a pin sticking me.
How come I have to have
these straps on, doc?
Well, you see, Petro,
i'’m trying a new formula.
I wouldn'’t want you to make
a sudden move
and fall off the couch.
But Don'’t worry, it'’ll only be
for a little while.
How do you feel now?
I feel just like
I always did.
When you stick me
with that thing...
- Kinda dopey.
- ... i'’m sleepy.
♪ Rock-a-bye monster
on the little bed ♪
♪ when you wake up
some townsfolk will be dead ♪
That'’s right...
Go to sleep.
He'’s changing.
Looks kinda like
Fred travalena now.
Kind of--
he'’s growing hair.
My god, he'’s turned him
into Abe Lincoln!
The rail splitter.
Wow.
Isaac Asimov!
Lecherous scientist.
Amish farmer.
Quaker oats man.
Dr. Cornelius
from "planet of the apes."
A cure for baldness
at last.
I'’m calling it
Helsinki formula.
- Line.
- Line!
Line, please.
Gentlemen, I wish you were here
to see the proof of my claim,
that the transfusion of blood
between different species
is possible.
A few moments ago,
Petro was a man.
A harmless,
good-natured man.
- Now bingo is his name-o.
- Look at him now.
He looks just like one
of the flying monkeys
from "the wizard of oz."
Now he'’s his own
best friend.
[Growling, muttering]
[Growling]
He'’s no longer human.
He'’s a wolf.
Snarling, ferocious.
Lusting for the kill.
He needs to go outside,
too, I think.
This is a scientific
miracle, gentlemen.
Hey, it'’s William s. Burroughs.
You'’re a madman, Cameron.
Your claim is
ridiculous.
That'’s exactly what you said
in the newspapers,
professor Blaine--
that I was a madman.
I may be mad,
but you'’re transparent.
... science chair
at the university.
Perhaps you'’ll change
your mind one day soon,
when Petro tears
at your throat.
Poppycock!
But look.
[Petro snarling]
I Don'’t think they should
let him get on the furniture.
He'’s getting all
tangled up.
Even now, he'’d like to be
at his work.
- Ripping out throats.
- My catalytic agent
has brought about
a complete transition
from man to wolf.
Your crazy experiments are
a disgrace to science.
- Mr. Mooney.
- Gail Gordon.
Those are the very words
you used in denouncing me
to the faculty.
Professor Fitzgerald...
Science!
What do you know
about science?
You with your hidebound
dogmas and shriveled mind
that refused to recognize
progress...
Hey, it'’s col. Potter.
Harry Morgan.
What is progress to you
with your foolish
tampering with nature?
I'’m glad you asked
that question,
professor Hatfield.
You also were one
of those stupid fools
who raised their voices
against me.
So he'’s talking to us.
I'’ve got a question.
But our armed forces
are not in combat
with a savage horde
who fight with fanatical fury!
Don'’t think he heard you.
Well, that fanatical fury
will avail them nothing
when I place my new serum
at the disposal
of the war department.
Just picture, gentlemen,
an army of wolfmen,
fearless, raging...
- Shedding.
Every man a snarling animal.
And an army of people
behind '’em
with pooper scoopers.
... millions of such
animal men.
Men who are governed
by one collective thought--
the animal lust to kill without
regard of personal safety.
[All]
Republicans?
Such an army will be
invincible, gentlemen.
Such an army will sweep
everything before it.
Your scheme is too
utterly fantastic, Dr. Cameron.
You'’re fools, all of you.
Four blind fools.
Especially you,
Dr. Warwick.
♪ Four blind fools ♪
How would you control
these wolfmen?
I'’ve perfected
an antidote
that induces the return
of immediate normalcy.
And I suppose that it would be
an easy matter
to round up a million
wild animals
and administer an antidote.
No, Cameron, you'’re mad.
Stark raving mad.
- And I for one am in favor--
- silence!
I have a whistle.
I'’m not interested
in your imbecilic mouthings.
All of you have demonstrated
your lack of vision
by demanding my resignation
from the faculty.
And your lack of bodies.
Well, you accomplished
your purpose.
You cast me out.
You robbed me of everything
that I held most dear in life--
- position, honor, respect.
- My own parking spot.
You branded me
as a madman.
Held me up to ridicule
before the whole world.
But now it'’s time
for my revenge.
- Petro will see to that.
- Sorry we said anything.
There'’s no escape
for any of you.
You shall die
one by one
at the hands
of he scientific marvel
that you scoffed at.
What a grouch.
You can'’t intimidate us
with fantastic threats.
You'’re a faker, Cameron,
a mad faker!
We'’ll have you ostracized
by every scientist
in the country.
There are institutions
for madmen.
Like the Pentagon.
And we'’ll see that you'’re
confined in one.
You would think, since
it was his imagination,
he'’d at least have them
be afraid of them.
They left.
He should have served drinks,
canapes, those little sandwiches
with the crust cut off.
- Nut cups.
- You will see, gentlemen.
You will see.
[Petro growling]
Next comes the ghost
of Christmas present.
Christmas present,
for me?
Okay, boy, okay,
i'’ll get you a liver snap.
[Petro snarling]
I hope he puts it
on his nose.
[Wolf howling]
What'’s the matter, boy?
Skippy.
♪♪
I'’d say skippy is what
he was eating.
♪♪
Look, I will revolutionize
shaving forever.
Hey, he looks okay.
Or as okay
as he ever will.
I bet his breath is
terrible, though.
But his mouth is cleaner
than yours and mine.
Tell me, doctor, how long
have I been asleep?
Oh, about an hour,
I should say.
That'’s seven hours
to you and me.
- How do you feel?
- I feel dog tired.
I have a terrible headache.
And I had some kind
of an awful dream.
I was running all over
the countryside,
chasing people
and trying to kill '’em.
What does a dream
like that mean, doctor?
Oh, that doesn'’t mean anything.
You just had a nightmare,
that'’s all.
But why should I be trying
to kill people?
Even in my dreams,
I ain'’t got nothin'’
against nobody.
Well, let'’s not talk
about it anymore.
Go to bed.
Our work'’s done for the night.
I set up some newspapers
in the corner for you.
All right, doc.
Duh, tell me about
the rabbits again, George.
And these are doors,
Petro.
- Evening, miss lenora.
- Good evening, Petro.
Well, night owl,
I was just coming down
to find out how much longer
you'’re going to work.
Do you realize
how late it is?
No, I didn'’t, I was
so absorbed in my work.
We done a lot
of work tonight.
And I slept almost an hour,
and I had the awfulest dream--
go to bed, Petro!
Yes, doctor.
Good night, miss lenora.
- Good night, Petro.
- I'’ll be lurking for you.
Dad, what kind of experiments
are you doing
that you need Petro?
Oh, he just helps me
in the laboratory
moving the heavy things around.
He'’s a very strong man
is Petro.
How much longer are we
gonna be here, dad?
Why?
'’cause the place
gets on my nerves.
I hate it.
Your hating it has nothing
to do with being separated
from that young reporter friend
of yours, has it?
It has.
And I want to know
when we'’re going back
to the city.
Very soon now, dear.
My work'’s practically finished.
[Petro howling]
What was that?
It was Petro,
talking in his sleep again.
- What?
- Well, that noise.
It sounded like
a wild animal howling.
I heard the same thing
last night.
Oh, that'’s probably
some dog in the neighborhood.
Dogs do howl, you know.
You mustn'’t let things
like that upset you.
Now, come along, dear...
She want to be Judy garland
in the worst way, doesn'’t she?
I think so.
Hey, it looks just like the
front of the munsters'’ house.
Without the charm.
Good morning, Petro.
Good mornin'’, miss lenora.
I was hopin'’ you'’d come
to the garden this mornin'’.
I got somethin'’ for ya.
It'’s a human head!
Oh, they'’re lovely.
Thank you.
I'’ll pick them for you
every day if you like '’em.
Well, that'’s very kind
of you.
I want you to meet my brother,
Fred gwynne.
What'’s the matter,
miss lenora?
Petro, I Don'’t like
this place.
No, I guess you feel
about this place
the same as I do.
I'’m a'’feared of it.
Especially at night,
when the mist comes up
out of the swamp.
Of course, it'’s all right
when the sun'’s shinin'’
like it is this mornin'’.
Are there any wild animals
around here?
- Just you, fur ball.
- There'’s lots of '’em.
- How come you ask?
- I was just curious.
Say, Petro, what do you do
when you work with dad
in the laboratory?
Oh, I sit, I roll over,
and I shake sometimes.
I Don'’t rightly know.
Besides, I ain'’t supposed
to tell none of it.
Your pop made me promise.
Well, you can trust me.
I wouldn'’t tell anybody.
Well, we--
cheese it, it'’s Alan Brady!
No, I ain'’t sayin'’ nothin'’.
Petro, did you fetch
the paper this morning?
- Good morning, dad.
- Did you sleep well?
Yes, very well.
Look at the flowers
that Petro gathered for me.
Very pretty.
I'’m afraid you'’ll have
to give up your gardening
for the time being, Petro.
- Aww.
- I want you in the laboratory.
Well, doc, if I Don'’t keep
at the stuff,
how am I ever gonna
make it look pretty?
And I like pretty things.
We shall leave this place
long before you'’re able
to beautify it.
The gardening really isn'’t
very important.
Come along with me.
Gardening always takes
a backseat to science.
Always.
Ah, Petro, I see you'’re
waiting for me.
[Wolf howling]
Hey, it'’s a dog bell.
You mustn'’t be so jumpy--
you'’re as nervous as that wolf.
He sure is...
- Is this like
mice and men
or flowers for algernon,
Joel?
Neither--
just keep watching.
Sorry.
And he ate [indistinct].
All right, lie down, Petro.
Are you gonna strap me down
again tonight, doc?
Well, certainly--
it'’s more necessary tonight
than ever before.
Gee, it must be great
to be educated.
I wish I had a lot
of book learnin'’, so...
So I could strap people
down, too.
Fortunately, you Don'’t need
education or intelligence
for your part
of the experiment.
Just strength...
Animal strength.
Now, lie down,
and we'’ll get to work.
Now cough.
Seatbelts save lives.
The captain has turned off
the "no smoking" signs.
Feel free to roam
about the swamps.
[Wolf howling]
Oh, Petro?
There'’s a kitty
out in the yard.
♪♪
Stay, boy.
Do not disobey ape law.
[Growling]
[As frosty the snowman]
Happy birthday!
[Wolf howling]
[Snarling]
[Wolf growling]
Rahr!
It'’s a bowwow powwow.
Did I just see a Chuck wagon
roll through there?
Think he'’s got
morning phlegm.
It'’s a doggy door.
Outside, boy, outside.
Go on...
There you are.
Good doggy--
yes, you'’re a good doggy.
What a good doggy.
[Growling]
He'’s a good doggy,
isn'’t he, Joel?
Very good doggy, crow.
Really good doggy.
Excellent doggy.
That felt good.
Now i'’m gonna go turn
my daughter into a woodchuck.
Skipper!
Little buddy!
[Wolves howling]
What'’s he doing now?
[Howling]
I think he'’s marking
his territory.
[Crickets chirping]
Little buddy!
- Skipper!
Keep talkin'’!
Little buddy!
Skipper?
Little house in the swamp.
Well, wilbur'’s fed.
What'’s granny smokin'’?
I think it'’s borkum riff,
you guys.
All the animals are
terrible nervous tonight,
for some reason
or other.
The old plough mule
like to kick my head off.
I'’d like to do
the same thing.
... sort of quiet-like, and she
lashed out with both feet.
Then she fell down.
It'’s the devil mist
in the swamp.
Oh, I guess
it'’s not borkum riff.
Oh, will ya stop
talkin'’ like that?!
I'’m so nervous now,
I could scream.
Go with that feeling.
Okay, mommy,
i'’m all ready.
It'’s Shirley temple!
Now, you hop in bed.
Can I play with my ball,
just for a little while?
Well, just for a little while,
but mind,
if you ain'’t in bed
by the time I do the dishes,
i'’m gonna tan you good.
Don'’t worry, i'’ll be in bed
and fast asleep by that time.
Well, if she
starts tap-dancing, you guys,
i'’m gonna lose it,
I swear.
Sleep tight, Don'’t let
the wolf man bite.
I remember staying up
and just playing with my ball.
That was fun.
- Yeah?
- It'’s worth staying up for.
You never stayed up.
Okay, it'’s not a real memory,
but...
[Sniffles]
I can dream, can'’t I?
Looks like he'’s inside
the doctor'’s heart
in that movie,
"fantastic voyage."
[Whistling]
♪ Come and listen to a story
'’bout a man named jed ♪
♪ a poor mountaineer,
barely kept his family fed ♪
♪ then one day, he was shootin'’
at some food ♪
♪ and up from the swamp
came a big, ugly dude ♪
- [Snarling]
- ♪ wolfman, that is ♪
♪ black teeth,
gnarled face ♪
♪ well, the next thing
you know ♪
♪ old jed'’s really scared ♪
♪ the kinfolk said, "jed,
get away from there" ♪
♪ said, "my cabin is
the place you ought to be ♪
♪ so he loaded up his drawers
and he told his family ♪
♪♪
Good one, crow.
Servo.
Over here.
Oh, yeah, that'’s right.
Good one, servo.
You, too, crow.
Thanks, "ed."
I didn'’t do anything.
Help, help, help!
Help, mad dog!
Mad dog!
Shut the door, quick.
I never seen anything
so awful in my life.
What are you talking about?
The first part of the movie,
it was terrible!
What was it?
- Mmm.
- I Don'’t know if it was a man,
a beast,
or old Satan himself.
I'’ll have a Shirley temple
to go, please.
The kid'’s history.
I let him have both barrels
of my shotgun, but that...
She'’s stoned--
whistler'’s mother is stoned.
Ya can'’t kill '’em, no ways.
Looks like popeye
finally got that operation
he always wanted.
I'’m tellin'’ ya,
it was somethin'’ awful.
How about a little ball,
scarecrow?
♪♪
[Mother screams]
Clothing from
the junior sample collection.
[Growling]
Little buddy.
Skipper!
Heh, what do you think
of my little film so far?
Pretty good, huh?
[Chuckling]
♪♪
Ah, my favorite part...
The whipping.
Ooh, I better cut down
on those Shirley temples.
♪♪
[Snarling]
Petro!
Lie down on that couch.
[Growling]
Lie down!
Sit... stay.
No, jump through
the flaming hoop.
I'’ve seen better dog acts
on the old Sullivan show.
Time for your kickback,
Petro.
Lot of good acting
in this scene.
Down!
That'’s a beautiful fade.
That really works
as a device, I think.
They only had enough money for
one full makeup sequence,
I guess.
Have I been walking
in my sleep again?
Well, that
and a few other things.
You'’d better go to bed.
I'’m sorry if I made
a nuisance of myself.
I wish I wouldn'’t
walk in my sleep,
but that'’s because
I have such bad dreams.
Not as bad as your breath.
I think
it'’s the kid in him.
You'’ve been of great assistance
to me tonight.
Very great assistance.
In fact,
i'’m going to reward you
by taking you to the city
with me.
We'’re going
to obedience school, Petro.
I can go along with you
and ride in the car?
- Gotta go.
- Let'’s get out of here.
While we'’re in the city,
we'’ll make calls
together.
Tell me about
the rabbits again, Joel.
We will call upon a pompous
gentleman called Blaine.
Professor Blaine.
Joel, is the wolf man actually
eating his victims,
or is he just simply
mauling them in this movie?
Well, that'’s one thing we Don'’t
know Tom servo.
You know, back then,
all the violence was implied.
You know?
Today on earth,
there'’s nothing left
to the viewer'’s imagination
in movies, you know.
It'’s not at all uncommon
to see a complete
onscreen evisceration
in complete dolby stereo sound
and widescreen technicolor.
Wow, that really
sounds neat.
But, Joel,
say a wolf man eats a guy.
A normal person weighs in
about 150 or 200 pounds.
Does that mean the wolf man
weighs 300 to 400 pounds
after just one meal?
Well, uh, what you have
to understand, crow,
is that this
is a science fiction movie.
It'’s pretend--
it'’s not real.
Besides, a human being
can'’t eat
a whole other human being.
At least,
not in one setting.
Especially if he fills up
on bread first.
- Right, yeah.
- Oh, hey, Joel.
What if this guys goes
into this thing a vegetarian.
Does he start rampaging
victory gardens?
Does he become the terror
of the produce aisle?
Yeah, and say a guy
changes back to normal
before swallowing a mouthful
of townsfolk.
Does that
make him a cannibal,
or just a meat-and-potatoes
werewolf?
Crow, it'’s science fiction.
Oh, yeah, we'’re supposed
to suspend our disbelief.
- Hmm.
- Right.
What if they ordered a hoagie
at a restaurant,
and there was a hair in it?
What would happen?
Well, uh, remember,
he is a wolf man,
so he probably
wouldn'’t send it back,
unless it was a ponytail
or something like that,
you know.
- Yuck.
- Uck, ugh.
Has there ever been
an instance of an animal
being turned into
a human being?
Oh, on earth?
No, not that I know of.
What about Kenny Rogers?
Yeah, Barry gibb.
Yeah, c. Everett koop.
Or that big guy
from the oak Ridge boys.
Moms mabley.
[Buzzer]
[All]
Movie sign!
[Rain falling]
Well, come on in, Tom.
Glad to see you.
- Good evening, Dr. Blaine.
- Maybe Johnny cash?
Um, uh, Harvey fierstein.
Gino vannelli.
Um... hmm...
Buddy Schultz?
- Shh!
- I have a faint suspicion
- that there is something...
- Robin Williams.
... besides my housekeeper'’s
welfare on your mind.
- What is it?
- Well, i'’m after a story.
Well, quite a novel pursuit
for a newspaperman.
An a.P. Dispatch
from Ashton
down in the swamp country
tells about a child
being killed by a wild animal.
Oh, that'’s a tragedy.
Yes, a neighboring farmer
saw the brute,
and swears that it
traveled at a terrific speed
on its two hind legs.
I understand they make
a very potent corn liquor
in that district.
Duh, it'’s more
of a Shirley temple.
I have a hunch
there'’s more to this story
than just a jugful
of corn liquor.
I hoped that you
could give me an angle.
It was several jugs.
I Don'’t know
what you mean by an angle.
The possibility of the survival
in the depths of the swamp
of some of those
overgrown lizards
that used to be
head man on earth.
I understand they traveled
around on their hind legs
and made our present-day
public enemies
look like
horticultural specimens.
What is Hollywood producers?
I can'’t lend myself to that sort
of sensationalism.
True science,
the search for knowledge,
is on a far higher plane
than that.
It is worthy of being
treated with dignity.
And I feel that I owe
an obligation
to the people
who respect my opinion.
Your, um, "angle,"
as you call it,
on prehistoric lizards
is utterly fantastic.
Oh, you like it?
I'’m sorry,
I didn'’t know
I was getting into
such deep water.
Well, i'’ll hang my head in shame
and slink away.
Now, no harm done.
Don'’t take it so to heart.
Put your feet up on the desk
and stay for a while.
Oh, I can'’t now, i'’ve got
to get back to the office.
But i'’ll drop around
again.
Thanks very much
for the information.
I didn'’t give you very much.
Bye, dagwood!
[Door closes]
Hi, clock.
[Clock chimes]
Time flies when you can'’t
write script parts.
- Or edit.
- You know, I never understand
these "fireside" comics.
There'’s a caveman and a bear
and, uh...
[Knocking on door]
Oh!
[Knocking continues]
Who is it?
- Hello, friend.
- [Humming ominous music]
- Surprised to see me?
- Yes, I confess I am.
Come in, sit down.
Thank you.
You shouldn'’t
be surprised, Blaine.
I told you that i'’d come back
when I could prove my theory
to your
complete satisfaction.
You say you'’ve proven
that wild theory?
Well, i'’m here.
You Don'’t think I enjoyed
your comments so much
that I came back merely
to hear you repeat them?
Joel, what did he do wrong,
anyway?
Oh, he was
the one out of five doctors
who didn'’t choose bayer,
crow.
Oh.
... any statement proven
to be untrue.
Do you think that
will cancel your obligation?
Do you think a retraction
will pay me
for the humiliation of being
held up to public ridicule?
For having my scientific
reputation blasted?
For being forced to resign
from an honorable position?
Oh, chill out,
Mr. Salty.
I deeply regret
any possible injustice.
But my rejection
of your theory
was not intended
as a personal persecution.
I'’m sorry, i--
it wasn'’t a love note,
either.
I supposed we'’re all prone
at times to lose sight
of the true perspective.
Well, let'’s
say no more about it.
I'’ll gladly say anything
in support of your theory.
I'’m not asking you to take
my word for anything.
Just believe the evidence
of your own eyes.
Petro.
[Imitating lurch]
You rang?
Hey, you made the hat fit!
Petro, you sit here.
My gimmick.
So what?
You made a big dumb guy.
Sit on the cedar chips,
fella.
You have any shiny objects
for my friend over here?
You are aware
of the nature of this?
We'’ve been doing this
a long time.
You may rest assure,
the experiment
is a proven success.
Otherwise,
I wouldn'’t be here.
What good can
come with tampering
with the normal laws
of nature?
- Teflon?
- Uh, microwave milkshakes?
Room air fresheners.
You'’ll understand
when you see the results.
I abhor whatever appears to be
a perversion of science.
Mingling the blood
of man and beast
is downright sacrilege.
Tell that to the NFL.
I have no sympathy with such
maudlin sentimentality.
I propounded a theory
which you denounced publicly
as being ridiculous,
the result
of a disordered mind.
Are you trying to squirm
out of facing
the possibility
that you may be wrong?
Not at all.
I will cooperate
in any way possible.
Then you take
the injection.
Just what I wanted to hear.
I'’ve given him
one injection
to prepare his blood
for the transfusion.
He'’ll need another...
In exactly 20 minutes.
He'’s hearing sounds
that we can'’t hear.
He'’s getting a whiff
of his own overalls.
They must be pretty gamey
by now.
[Phone ringing]
[Lifts receiver]
Hello?
Is this magnolia 3-7136?
I'’d like to speak
to Dr. Lorenzo Cameron, please.
Uh, just a moment, please.
It'’s for you, Cameron.
They want to know if we have
prince Albert in a can.
Let me take it--
I love that bit.
Oh, is that you, dear?
You asked me to call you
and find out if you'’re
returning tonight.
It'’s all right, i'’ll be home
as soon as I can.
Good-bye.
That dad of mine.
God, he'’s nutty.
... friends, i'’ll have
to go and get her.
I shan'’t be long.
What about the second
injection?
You said it had
to be given in 20 minutes.
Oh, yes, the injection.
I may be able
to make it.
If not, I wonder, doctor,
whether you'’d do it for me.
Why, uh...
Yes, I guess so.
That'’s very, very kind
of you.
Petro, you stay here and Don'’t
bother Dr. Blaine.
No, sir,
I won'’t bother him.
Of course, it'’s quite
possible, doctor,
if I Don'’t get back
that you could ensure
the failure
of this demonstration
by forgetting
his injection.
I'’ll have
to take that chance.
Don'’t worry.
Even if I lacked
a sense of honor,
pride would hardly
allow me
to stoop to such a level.
I shall give him the injection
if you'’re not here by 12:00.
At 12:00, precisely.
Oh, and if
he gets hungry,
there'’s some jerky treats
in his knapsack.
Big jerky treats.
Who'’s he calling?
The s.P.C.A.
What'’s the s.P.C.A., crow?
Uh, society for the prevention
of the cruelty of actors.
- Oh.
- Heh heh heh.
Good one, servo.
Nice setup.
- Hello?
- Ba-boom!
Yeah, is that you, Blaine?
- What you want to drag me...
- Just call him hemmingway.
... out of bed at this time
of the night, for?
I'’ve just had
a surprising visitor.
Lorenzo Cameron.
Better than Lorenzo lamas.
He claims to have
proven his crazy,
outlandish blood transfusion
theory
and demands the right
to give a demonstration.
- Yay!
- Yeah.
Is Dave there?
No, he'’s-- no.
No, he'’s not here now.
When'’s he
gonna be back?
He'’ll be back after 12:00.
Why Don'’t you
come on over?
- Is there gonna be beer?
- All right.
I'’ll get dressed
and be over right away.
Expect me in about
ten minutes.
Nice jammies.
Are you at all familiar
with the work
Dr. Cameron is doing?
Oh, no, sir.
I'’m just handyman
around the place.
Nobody, not even
miss lenora,
knows what he does.
Oh, his daughter is still
with him?
Oh, yes, sir,
she'’s with him.
But I think she'’s lonesome.
She seems to be
grievin'’ about somethin'’.
Kind of like a big,
dumb Andy Griffith, isn'’t he?
... no right to accept such
a sacrifice from her.
Well, a big Andy Griffith.
- Andy Griffith?
- I Don'’t like being busybody,
but she'’s such a fine girl
and...
Just plain old
Andy Griffith.
Yeah.
... just the tonic she needs
to make her happy.
Where do they live?
Oh, Dr. Cameron rented the old
danfield homestead house,
about four or five
miles from Ashton.
It was a fine place,
but ain'’t been nobody
lived there for a long time,
and the weeds kept growing
closer to the house
till they about
swallowed up everything.
Petro, give me a hand.
My thumbs are caught
in my vest.
Oh, that'’s good.
I'’m prescribing a weed eater
and some turf-builder, Petro.
Oh, and a lawnmower.
Take this
to a hardware store.
Blaine just told me that you
wanted to demonstrate
the proof of your
blood transfusion theory.
He exaggerated when
he mentioned demonstration.
I told him I could
prove my claim.
But I Don'’t think
professor Blaine
is in a cooperative
frame of mind.
- Cooperative.
- That'’s why I came to you.
What do you
want me to do?
I'’d like you to be present
when I talk to him.
All right, i'’ll take
a walk over with you.
You know, uh...
Wood spikes, some of
those beefsteak tomatoes.
That last scene was blocked like
a bad high school play.
Hmm...
A pair of wellies,
then we can use your hat
as a composter.
[Clock chiming]
It'’s injection time!
This should take a while.
12 bings and a sharp
pain in the arm.
Just shoot him.
You told him you would.
Don'’t pad your part.
No, he'’s back there.
Hey, turn around.
He'’s not in the yard.
No.
No, it'’s the big dumb guy
in the chair.
This is his big scene.
His last big shot before
all his hair is gone.
- Finally found him.
- I heartily disapprove
of the nature
of this experiment,
but my promise
to Dr. Cameron
leaves me no alternative.
Sure.
Roll up your sleeve.
It'’s the original
"sid and Nancy."
How do you feel?
- Just like I always do.
Kind of dopey.
Line.
He'’s looking
right at his script.
- Line.
- Hey.
Well, his eyes
rolled back in his head.
Well, here we are.
Ohh.
- Something wrong?
- It'’s his pen.
It just opened up
in his coat pocket.
Heart trouble.
Nothing serious, but...
Stressing, at times.
I'’ll be all right
after I rest a bit.
Yes, I like
green eggs and ham.
Thank you, thank you,
Sam I am.
Maybe you better read him
"go, dog. Go!"
That'’s it, Petro.
From here to there,
from there to here.
Maybe we'’d better
go in the house.
Oh, no, it'’s...
In-- in just a moment.
What'’s the matter-- drunk?
Nope, scientist.
Want me to call
an ambulance?
No, I Don'’t want an ambulance.
I'’ll be... all right
in a minute.
Well, I was
just trying to help.
♪♪
This Dr. Seuss, god,
he kills me.
[Chuckling]
♪♪
Wake up, boy.
[Whistling]
Wake up.
Whoa.
Hey, it'’s wishbone
from the old "rawhide" show.
♪♪
He'’s doing his cagney.
You dirty rat.
You'’re the man
who murdered my brother.
You dirty rat.
I'’m gonna rip your head off
like an all-day sucker.
[Monster snarling]
What'’s that?
Sounded like it come
from the house!
Come on in here--
there'’s something wrong.
Jim never drinks coffee
at home.
I'’ll say there'’s
something wrong.
No, i'’ll say there'’s
something wrong!
There'’s something wrong.
Get me police headquarters,
and make it fast.
Hello, sarge,
this is dugan.
- I got a murder on my hands.
- Finally...
I get my harmonica back.
- It'’s got spit all over it.
- Right away!
That'’s the work of an animal,
not of a human being.
What do you
know about this?
How could I know anything?
I was with you.
Why so defensive then?
Officer, my heart'’s beginning
to trouble me again.
I can'’t be of any use here.
I may as well leave.
Sure, go ahead.
I can'’t pretend
to feel any great sorrow.
But then, my feelings
are of no importance,
one way or the other.
Nobody loves me,
everybody hates me.
Think i'’ll go eat worms.
What a kook.
Whew!
- Howdy, lieutenant.
- Hi.
I'’ve seen
a lot of murders in my day,
but never as messy
as this one.
This was no
boating accident.
This was a shark.
This should make a gory enough
story for your paper.
This is more
than just a story to me.
He was my friend.
It'’ll make a great story.
Maybe even a movie,
with a sequel.
... college professors
arguing outside
and using
a lot of big words.
They followed me in here.
And I heard one of them
say that
some kind of
a dangerous animal
done this killing.
Well, how could
a dangerous animal
be roaming around the city?
I Don'’t know--
must have got away from a zoo
or a circus or something.
What'’s this-- "mulch,
turf-builder, leaf bags"?
Hmm.
Maybe i'’ll just remove
this evidence from the scene.
- Ashton... Ashton...
- Ashton.
- You talking to me?
- We all fall down.
- No, no, i'’m just trying
to remember something.
Ashton...
I got it.
An a.P. Story came in
from Ashton the other day
about a--
about a child being killed
by a weird animal
from the swampland.
What do you mean,
"weird animal"?
Platypus or a jackalope--
you know, weird.
... it traveled on two legs,
like a man.
Ah, he was crazy or drunk.
There ain'’t
no such animal.
Anyway, how could he
get way up here?
I wish I knew.
Reel change...
Reel change!
Thank you.
[Wolf howling]
Tell me about it.
You think you got problems.
None of my clothes
fit anymore.
[Howling continues]
♪♪
And they'’ll never be able
to get a serious role.
[Chuckling]
Do you think I look like
Victor mature?
She smells him first.
Petro,
you startled me!
Oh, what'’s the matter?
Why do you stare at me
like that?
He'’s wondering
what you'’d look like on rye.
I Don'’t know,
miss lenora.
I feel funny.
I smell something in the mist,
coming up out of the swamp.
It'’s like
a voice talking to me,
telling me to do
something.
Something terrible.
Oh, but that isn'’t real.
That'’s just
your imagination.
You mustn'’t pay
any attention
to what that voice
seems to be saying.
Petro!
Bad dog!
You know you'’re always
supposed to be in the kitchen.
Go to your room.
You'’ve no right
in this part of the house.
Get out!
Immediately!
- Reallybad dog.
- Wake up!
You'’re dreaming.
Get a muzzle.
For the doctor.
I Don'’t know
what'’s come over me.
I must have a touch
of swamp fever.
That'’s very likely.
Now go to bed.
I'’ll get something for you.
- Yes, sir.
- I had a marsh rash once.
I'’m sorry if I made
a nuisance of myself.
Dad, what happened
to Petro?
I'’m terribly afraid.
There'’s nothing
to be afraid of, dear.
He just had a touch
of fever, that'’s all.
That was more than fever.
Why, his eyes were
the eyes of a wild beast.
He was possessed
by a demon.
Now, dear, you know
there'’s no such thing
as being possessed
by a demon.
That'’s an old superstition.
Well, I Don'’t care
what you call it, dad.
But there'’s something here
that'’s evil.
It'’s real,
and I can feel it.
And i'’m afraid!
It makes me want to sing.
... any longer.
Let'’s get away.
I can'’t go now, dear, I must
wait till my work'’s finished.
Pull yourself together,
dear.
Oh... I won'’t
be silly anymore.
Nothing must interfere
with your work.
You'’ve been
a very great help to me.
I know what a terribly lonely
life this must be for you.
We won'’t talk about it
anymore, dad.
I just want you to prove
that you'’re the greatest
scientist in the world.
They'’ll soon have
all the proof they want.
I expect we plan on
professor Fitzgerald
to pay me a call
before long.
And I shall be
delighted to confound him
with scientific facts that
he declared were impossible!
[Chuckles]
Now, you go to bed,
dear, huh?
Have a good night'’s rest?
Good night, dear.
Right, i'’ll get
some warm milk.
Good night, dad.
What a kook.
Nice caboose
on that girl.
What am I saying--
that'’s my daughter!
I am mad.
[Snarling]
Poor Petro wants to be
out with his friends,
people of his own kind,
playing and killing.
That'’s the life.
Boy, they'’re getting a lot
of use out of that swamp set,
aren'’t they?
Yeah, but it'’s not fog
hanging in the air,
it'’s body odor.
It'’s kind of like an early
music video, isn'’t it?
Yeah, before
they invented action.
Or Paula Abdul.
[Knocking on door]
Look at that lantern.
That ladder casts a shadow
in the wrong direction.
Hi... sorry to bother you
this time of night,
but i'’ve lost my way.
Come on in.
Water'’s fine.
- Sit down.
- Sit a spell.
Take your shoes off.
You'’re a fool to be
traveling around
by yourself
at night like this,
when the mist comes up
from the swampland.
Oh, you mean
the mysterious night prowler
that'’s got everyone'’s
imagination working overtime?
It ain'’t imagination
with me, mister.
It'’s a way of life.
That thing killed
my little girl.
I'’m sorry, i--
I wouldn'’t have joked
if i'’d known--
scared jed Harper so bad,
he went and got religion.
But I hear there'’s
a cure for that.
Can you give me
some facts about this killer?
What does it look like?
No one can tell you that
for sure, mister.
'’cause it never prowls--
only on nights like this
when the mist is thick.
And nothing can be
seen very plain.
Jed Harper said
it traveled on two legs.
But you can'’t count on that,
'’cause jed was scared
half out of his mind.
And he'’s an idiot.
Besides, the mist was
extra-thick that night.
You better stay here
the rest of the night, mister.
I can'’t offer you a bed,
but i'’ll make you
as comfortable as I can.
Well, thank you
very much.
You can sleep on me.
Oh, are you still here?
He'’s looking for
his favorite tree.
Stick around,
there'’s plenty more film.
That'’s the most casually-dressed
monster i'’ve ever seen.
Not really prowling,
he'’s just kind of wandering.
Not this again.
Looks like, uh...
I Don'’t know if you
can tell in that shot,
but I think Petro'’s doing
something new with his hair.
Maybe some new mousse.
Maybe it'’s a deer.
If I have to
keep you in a cage,
you'’re of no further
use to me.
You'’ll revert
without my knowledge
and become dangerous.
I hadn'’t thought
of that possibility.
On your couch,
Petro!
[Snarling]
Now!
Couch...
Couch, Petro, couch.
You know, there'’s
gonna come a day
when he'’s just
not gonna do that anymore.
Spare the whip
and spoil the wolf.
I Don'’t know,
Petro took, like,
a shotgun blast
to the chest,
but he'’s afraid of a whip.
Something'’s wrong.
He'’ll never be a show dog
at this rate.
♪♪
That'’s not
the normal syringe.
[Snarling]
Who?
Time for your
booster shot.
I couldn'’t disappoint
professor Fitzgerald.
♪♪
Not a very decisive
mad scientist, is he?
Down, Petro!
Down!
That is the right way
to administer a shot.
Just tie off
the arm, find the vein,
knee on his chest,
and make sure
to line up
your shin with his sternum.
Line.
Did I walk
in my sleep again?
Yes.
Doctor, ain'’t there some way
you could cure me
from doing that?
I'’m afraid not.
It may be necessary
to lock you up at night
after this.
That Don'’t seem fair
to lock a man up,
just like he was an animal.
Neutering often helps
ease a bad temper.
You could stand Petro'’s overalls
in a corner.
... home with a jug
under his arm last night.
That'’s a really bad toupee.
He'’ll never lift
another jug.
We have this scene on
a commemorative plate, you know.
Yeah.
And he wasn'’t a pretty sight
to look at, neither.
There must be some natural
explanation
for this thing
you'’re talking about.
It'’s a werewolf.
You can'’t get him no way,
except by a silver bullet.
[All]
Shut up!
I'’m not giving that story
to the city editor.
He'’d throw me
right out on my ear.
That killer ain'’t human.
You'’d know that
from one look at the body.
I saw a victim of just
such an attack.
I wonder if there
could be a possibility
of any connection
between them.
[All]
Nah!
I'’ve been telling you
all along,
it'’s the form of a human
who sold his soul to the devil.
- That'’s Tom waits'’ mom.
- In the light of day,
he walks like
any other man on the earth.
At night, he takes on
the form of a wolf!
[All]
Shut up!
Then you never heard
of any killings...
- Ooh...
- By strange animals around here
until recently?
Why does he keep
asking me all them questions?
Well, all newspapermen
are like that.
He doesn'’t mean
anything by it.
He'’s just a jerk.
You go ahead--
he won'’t bother you anymore.
Yes, miss.
Lenora, you must
give some thought
to your own safety
and peace of mind.
There'’s no normal reason
for Dr. Cameron to hide away
in a place like this,
unless--
unless what?
Oh, nothing.
Forget it.
Don'’t avoid the question.
What were you
going to say?
I was gonna say, "unless he'’s
hiding something," okay?
Get off my back.
That creature is responsible
for the horrible killings
in this vicinity,
and I think the same creature
killed professor Blaine.
Well, that'’s a terrible thing
for you to say.
I didn'’t expect you to join
the chorus against him.
I had to join the chorus--
i'’m a great tenor.
I hope i'’m wrong,
but i'’ll do everything I can
to learn the truth,
no matter where it leads.
Good morning, young man.
I'’m very glad to see you.
I want to apologize for the way
I talked to you last night.
Oh, well,
that'’s all right.
I-- I can understand
how you must feel
about the newspapers.
It isn'’t what you call
"hang on with their punches"?
"Pull their punches."
I know-- they gave you
quite a ride.
It was the way
he was treated in "doonesbury"
that got him really mad.
I'’m so sorry,
the way I received you.
If you'’re interested
in scientific research,
i'’d be glad sometime to show you
what i'’ve accomplished.
Well, thanks, doc,
that'’s very nice.
Now, if you'’ll pardon me,
i'’ll leave lenora
to entertain you.
Well, okay.
I gotta go.
That doesn'’t sound like there'’s
a secret to hide, does it?
Why, no.
I'’m getting really
antsy watching this.
I never before was
so glad to be wrong.
[Mechanical whooshing,
whirring, and clanking]
Is this funny, Joel?
Is this supposed to be funny?
You'’ll notice i'’m not
laughing, Joel.
Hey, take it easy,
Tom servo.
It'’s just an experiment in
transmogrificational aconthropy,
just like in the film
we'’re watching, you know?
A human being with
the features of a wolf.
That'’s what'’s going on here.
Oh, so it means
i'’m supposed to go
roaming around the countryside,
ravaging people?
- No.
- I look like a geek, Joel.
No, Don'’t worry about it.
Just think of it like this--
you'’re my servo-Croatian.
- Yeah, that'’s it.
- Servo-Croatian?
Very funny-- you turned us
into mutants for a pun, Joel.
Not funny.
Real mature.
Wow, what a party!
Wow, I had this
weirdest dream, guys.
I-- I dreamt I was ray milland
on rosey greer'’s body.
[Laughing]
Hey-- hey, uh, servo.
You look great.
That upper body is really cu--
hey, wait a minute, pal,
that'’s my body!
Hey, when I said you could
borrow some of my stuff,
I didn'’t mean my torso!
- Take it easy.
- Listen, crow,
here'’s the story.
Dr. Joel f. Frankenstein
here
thought it'’d be very, very funny
to switch our heads around.
Oh, great-- so you look like an
erector set with a goiter,
and i'’ve got a body
dogs can'’t resist.
Oh, that'’s real funny.
You know what else
is real funny?
I just filled
your load pan.
- Oh, yeah?
- Hey, come on, come on.
Take it easy--
it'’s an experiment.
Just tell me how you feel.
Well, do you want to know
where my head'’s at, Joel?
Or do you want
his gut reaction?
[Laughter]
- Hey!
[Both in unison] Are you
thinking what i'’m thinking?
If you like long walks
in the rain...
Chinese food...
Mushing up
your ice cream...
- Oh, yes, we love us!
[Both] Our collective brains
are more powerful than Joel.
There'’s nothing that can
stand in our way.
We have seen the future,
and it is us.
Massage us into your scalp.
We are one, all one,
all powerful.
Yes, we are servo-Croatian,
and we shall rule the wor--
[click]
My robots--
I think i'’ll keep '’em...
Turned off.
♪♪
[Knocking]
See, it was easy to switch
your heads back.
Thanks, Joel.
I Don'’t want to talk
about it.
Uh-oh, these-- oh.
Into my seat--
i'’m comfy now.
Oh, professor Fitzgerald!
How is the world did you
find your way down here?
Zelda drove me.
Your father wrote,
asking me to come.
- Is he here?
- Yes.
And he'’ll be very glad to see
one of his old friends.
Ah, Fitzgerald, it is
an unexpected honor.
I hardly dared hope that
you'’d accept my invitation.
Well, if you'’ve made a
worthwhile scientific discovery,
I want to be the first
to congratulate you.
I shall be delighted to
give you that opportunity.
Well, the things that you two
have to talk over
are way over my head,
so i'’ll leave you alone.
Oh, now, Don'’t run away.
I promise to limit myself
to words of two syllables.
That'’ll take all the fun
out of it.
Stop patronizing me,
you dork.
- I'’ll see you after a while.
- Okay.
Shall we go into the lab?
If you wish.
Oh, through the bookcase,
huh?
Wish I had me one of them
bookcase doors.
[Growling]
You'’re very "secreetive"
about your work.
No, secretive.
I like to keep out
intruders.
You seem to be
excellently equipped.
Thank you-- I didn'’t
think you could tell
through these trousers.
Sit down, won'’t you,
professor?
Thanks.
I'’ve discovered that certain
extremely volatile elements
in the blood,
little more than particles
of electrical energy,
are the source of all
physical growth and mentality.
By exciting the various
glands and brain cells...
Sounds painful.
I'’ve learned how to extract
and concentrate these elements
from the blood
of various animals.
I can control evolution.
I'’ve discovered
the source of life!
Deep dish pizza?
You'’re crazy.
Oh, I wouldn'’t say that
to him if I were you.
[Laughing]
That has a familiar ring.
You told the newspapers
I was crazy once, didn'’t you?
I didn'’t know that you
invited me here
to reopen an old controversy
that was very disagreeable...
- Is that Mel blanc?
- To all concerned.
I came with the hope that you'’d
abandoned impossible theories
and accomplished something
worthy of consideration.
Nice nostrils.
And I suppose you feel
yourself fully competent
to judge
my accomplishments--
you and your hide-bound
associates,
Hatfield, Warwick,
and Blaine!
Associates, and they'’re
very "secreetive."
Now, Blaine,
he no longer is passing
judgment on my sanity.
I believe you know something
about Blaine'’s death.
You were at his house.
You talked to him
on the telephone
before I came
to your house.
Did he say then
that he was in any danger
of losing his life?
No, nothing threatened him
at that time.
Oh, very good point.
And I was with you
when he was killed.
Okay, another good point.
You pride yourself on not
indulging in fantastic theories.
What proof have you that
I was in any way implicated
in Blaine'’s death?
I have no definite proof.
You accuse me of being crazy
for what I claim
to have accomplished
with this apparatus,
but I can give you overwhelming
proof of what I say.
I can inject into your veins
a substance
that will give you
the strength of ten men.
And their hair.
Or, following the line
of evolution,
how would you like a pair
of donkey'’s ears?
Oh, nice quip.
You really tagged him there.
I certainly will not
be the subject
for any of your experiments,
and i'’m afraid it'’s useless
for us to continue this
discussion any further.
You'’re not leaving,
are you?
I see no reason for staying.
Open that secret panel.
So you Don'’t care to stay
and be convinced
that you were wrong.
I Don'’t care to be ridiculed
by a charlatan.
Or you.
Ah, ridicule-- that isn'’t
pleasant, is it?
I know from experience.
I had nothing
to do with that.
It wasn'’t my fault if the public
treated your crazy theories
with the ridicule
they deserved.
Hey, Don'’t slam the bookcase
on the way out, pal.
Can'’t you see he'’s hurting?
- Fitzgerald!
- Well?
- Would you do me a favor?
- What is it?
Good time to ask for
a favor.
I have to send
my hired man into town.
Do you mind taking him
with you?
All right-- I can do that
without any trouble.
Oh, thank you so much.
If you'’ll wait in the car,
i'’ll send him out to you
in a few minutes.
Hope your car seats
are scotchgarded.
Make sure to leave
the window open a crack.
Now,
get in the car, Petro.
Don'’t keep professor
Fitzgerald waiting.
I should have known this trip
would be a waste of time.
I still hope to give you proof
that you can'’t ignore.
Remember me to Hatfield and
Warwick when you see them again.
[Engine starting]
Bye.
See you again.
[Snickering]
Why does he have to kill them
to prove his point?
Can'’t he just show them a pie
chart or something?
Why did professor Fitzgerald
leave so soon?
He wasn'’t impressed
by the possibilities
in my line of research.
Oh, well,
Don'’t be disappointed.
That'’s no credit
to his intelligence.
You'’re a great scientist,
and someday you'’re going
to startle the world.
You'’re right, dear-- i'’ll
startle the world.
By making
an even worse film.
Oh, great,
now she'’s locked out.
[Howling]
Mmm, peas and carrots,
peas and carrots, mmm!
Hey, everybody try to stay
in the shot this time.
[Howling]
Boy, they should make
the swamp set a lot bigger.
[Grumbling]
Whoa, slow down, pal.
Now, you guys, if he
turns into a werewolf,
is he gonna want to stick
his head out the window?
- Yep.
- Think so?
Any self-respecting
werewolf would.
Dogs can'’t resist it.
♪♪
[Laughing]
What a funny serum.
[Chuckling]
[Laughing]
♪♪
That'’s fun.
Mm-hmm.
♪♪
Keep your eye on
the windshield wiper, Petro.
It'’s not even raining.
Why are the windshield wipers
going?
Your eyes
are getting heavy.
So is this plot.
♪♪
Oh, very subtle. Very, very
nice. Nice camerawork.
I thought the windshield wiper
would obscure our vision.
♪♪
Wow, it looks like
hoyt axton, you guys.
It does-- he'’s gonna kill us
with "a cat name kalamazoo."
♪♪
Guess who'’s history
in this scene?
- That guy?
- Bingo.
[Growling]
Hey, Don'’t you know
you'’re not supposed to
talk to the driver--
let alone kill him
when he'’s driving?
Hey, that sounded like
it came from over there.
The swamp set.
♪♪
This one'’s a keeper.
Well, I guess
it'’s all right.
Humans wear mink stoles.
Gonna mount him
over the fireplace.
♪♪
[Growling]
Look, he'’s got
an all-day sucker.
He'’s mooning them.
I Don'’t think it counts if
you'’re mooning someone else
or using their moon
to do it.
♪♪
Helicopter spin--
do a helicopter spin.
That'’s an illegal hold.
- Look!
- [Gasping]
Don'’t shoot--
you'’ll hit the dead guy.
♪♪
[Growling]
That hurts.
[Gunfire]
♪♪
What the--
[mumbling]
♪♪
Professor Fitzgerald!
Is he dead?
He'’s still alive
but unconscious.
Where can we take him?
We can take him
over to my place.
The old danfield house
is handier.
We'’ll take him there.
I Don'’t know how badly
he'’s hurt.
One of you men
go for a doctor.
- Yeah, move his spine a lot.
- Hey, take it easy.
♪♪
Of course, it'’s a problem.
You turn your gardener
into a beast,
and the garden
goes to pot.
Dad, please come
to dinner.
You know I Don'’t
like to eat alone.
Oh, i'’m not very hungry.
You go ahead and go, dear.
Are you feeling discouraged
because professor Fitzgerald
was unsympathetic?
No, he'’s discouraged '’cause you
can'’t read your line, babe.
[Overlapping chatter]
[Knocking]
Here it is.
I'’ll answer it.
[Knocking]
Hey, dad,
the carolers are here!
What happened?
I found professor Fitzgerald
badly hurt.
It'’s a charivari.
It'’s a singing dead guy
telegram.
Oh, I didn'’t make any nog.
He'’s another victim of that
mysterious werewolf,
or whatever it is.
Now i'’m gonna have to kill him
all over again.
Well, he should be paralyzed
everywhere by now.
Bounce him down
and up a lot.
Easy, now.
Hmm.
Hey, can I have
this guy'’s suit?
The dead guy'’s glowing.
One of the men
went after a doctor.
He should be here
before long.
There'’s nothing more
we can do here,
so we'’ll keep hunting
for that killer.
You Don'’t need to come
down with us, ma'’am.
We can find our way out.
Good evening, sir.
That devil
got another victim.
Yes, so I see.
Nice job.
They'’re all in shock.
They'’ve never been
in such a bad film.
I was surprised to see
professor Fitzgerald
in this neighborhood.
He came to see me.
- How badly is he hurt?
- I Don'’t know yet.
We'’ll find out as soon
as the doctor gets here.
We'’ll know as soon
as we find his head.
If he regains consciousness,
we'’ll find out
who or what has committed
these horrible killings.
Yes.
It'’ll be very interesting to
hear what he has to say.
Yeah, real interesting.
[Howling]
Hey, here'’s that dog eating
peanut butter again.
Hmm, wait, I just lost
my bearings.
Okay, here'’s the end
of the swamp set,
and over there
is the mansion.
There'’s the director.
Hmm, no.
Well, hmm.
The door'’s ajar.
No, it'’s a door.
[Laughing]
I love that.
Since this awful thing
happened to him,
I can'’t feel any resentment
over the way he treated you.
Did you quarrel with him?
Yes, we quarreled.
So I suppose you think
that I went after him
and dragged him
out of the car.
Dad!
His newspaper training
seems to have made
a suspicious nature.
So defensive!
This movie really
kicks into high gear, I bet,
right about now.
Well, maybe not.
Hey, what'’s wolfman doing
down in the wine cellar?
He'’s trying to figure out
what kind of wine goes
with people, I think.
Oh.
[Thunder crashing]
I wish you wouldn'’t try
to antagonize him.
I wasn'’t trying
He didn'’t give me
a chance to finish.
I was just gonna ask him
if anyone was with Fitzgerald
when he left here.
Well, I can answer that.
Petro was with him.
Petro?
Yes, he drove him
into town.
Well, surely
you Don'’t think that--
I Don'’t know what to think.
And stop calling
me "Shirley."
But I will know as soon
as Fitzgerald comes to.
I'’m inclined to agree with dad
about your imagination.
It'’s fantastic.
Do you really like it?
But didn'’t it
strike you funny
that we didn'’t
find Petro around
when we found Fitzgerald?
Look, darling, please
Don'’t snap at me
just for trying
to add things up.
I'’m sorry.
It'’s arithmetic--
it always gets me.
Does the word "plodding"
mean anything to anyone?
He'’s still unconscious.
Oh, he must regain
consciousness,
even if only
for a few minutes.
He'’s throwing
a lot more light now.
That tie'’s loud enough
to wake up anyone!
That must be the doctor.
Oh, i'’ll go down with you.
Hey.
How'’d he get upstairs?
Oh, I think he'’s got an elevator
behind the fireplace.
Those mad scientists--
hoo!
They think of everything.
Oh, doctor, i'’m glad
you got here.
I'’m glad to get inside.
There'’s a humdinger
of a storm coming up.
Never actually seen
a dinger hum.
Upstairs.
It'’s raining cats and dogs.
You can go right on up.
You stay down here, dear.
There'’s nothing you can do.
I hate to leave you but
I must question Fitzgerald
as soon as he'’s able
to talk.
Hmm, a nice zinfandel?
No, maybe a Bordeaux.
What goes with scientists?
I reckon it'’s a little
late for me to help.
The man'’s dead.
Dead?
- Yes.
- That'’s too bad.
We were hoping
he'’d throw some light
on a matter
of great importance.
Well, i'’ll be getting
back to town
before this storm
gets worse.
I'’ll send the coroner out.
He could have phoned
that one in.
Yeah.
Hey, now she can clean
behind it.
That'’s gonna save a lot
of household drudgery.
You bet.
[Growling]
Hey, it'’s skipper.
Dad lied when he said he ran
over her with the car.
♪♪
Hmm.
And a comfort rest adjustable
bed with safety belts.
Dad'’s doing research
for art linkletter.
It'’s all starting
to come together now.
♪♪
Maybe a tawny port.
Oh, wait,
i'’ve got a bottle
of smothers brothers
wine right here.
[Thunder crashing]
Oh, bright.
Ooh, rain.
Rain is our friend.
What'’s behind
door number three?
♪♪
Aarrgh!
[Thunder crashing]
♪♪
He should have wore
a light wrap.
It'’s kind of chilly
in the basement there.
- Good night.
- Good night, doctor.
There'’s no necessity
for you to stay any longer.
Oh, yes, there is.
I want to ask you
a lot of questions,
mainly about Petro,
that servant of yours.
I Don'’t need to be bothered with
any more of your questions.
They'’re only prompted by
your fantastic imagination.
- Do you like it?
I must ask you to leave
at once.
We'’re doing some more talking
whether you like it or not.
You'’re making yourself
very unpleasant.
I haven'’t even started
yet to be unpleasant.
If my hunch is correct, i'’ll
prove you guilty of murder.
Then i'’ll throw my eyelids
inside out.
And in the meantime, i'’ll get
lenora out of this madhouse.
You will prove nothing.
He'’ll begin to smell
in a moment.
♪♪
I gotta know
what'’s behind that door.
Carol merrill, tell us
what they'’ve won.
The wolf or the man?
♪♪
Mystery date.
It'’s a wolfman, compliments
of spiegel catalog,
Chicago, Illinois 60609.
[Growling]
[Screaming]
Running like a bunny.
She'’s my kind of ghoul.
[Laughing]
[Shouting]
♪♪
Oh, now they can only seat
seven-- that'’s great.
♪♪
Upstairs!
Hey, he knows he'’s not supposed
to be in the house.
That is a nice hound'’s-tooth
jacket, though.
What happened to Petro?
[Laughing]
Huh.
♪♪
[Thunder crashing]
Now you guys know
what happens
if you leave your computer
plugged in.
Yeah.
Talk about a power surge.
Hey, how much more
of this film is there?
Well, you can tell right now
they'’re burning the main set,
so it should just be
a few more minutes, crow.
Okay.
Oh, so this is how
the other half lives--
the human half.
Well, his human half really
likes the flaky golden crust,
while the wolf in him
really enjoys
the seven vitamins
and minerals.
♪♪
I like that the wolfman'’s able
to keep his sport coat buttoned
through all of this.
♪♪
Petro.
Petro, what are you doing?
[Growling]
Well, i'’m thinking
about killing you.
Petro!
Stay back!
[Growling]
Petro!
Petro, stay back!
He'’s showing him how
that choke-chain feels.
And it Don'’t feel good.
♪♪
There'’s a lovely fire
in the fireplace.
And the rest
of the house.
Isn'’t it weird how
the whole house is on fire
and it'’s still
really dark?
Wait, wait, wait,
this is wrong.
Stop, drop, and roll.
Always.
I thought it was duck
and cover.
No, it'’s tuck and roll.
Wait.
Oh, I forgot my Teddy bear.
Dad!
Oh, you wait here.
I'’ll go get him.
Get the Teddy bear too!
[Crashing]
I Don'’t think
he'’s getting him now.
Yeah, I think that whole dad
thing is pretty well scratched.
Where--?
Oh, darling.
He'’s a briquette.
♪♪
Tomorrow'’s another day.
Mad monster meltdown.
We better
get out of here.
That was wonderful.
♪♪
[Mechanical whooshing,
whirring, and clanking]
All right, it'’s the end
of the movie, you two.
You know what happens--
say a good thing about the movie
and a bad thing about the movie,
you get ram chips, all right?
All right, okay, before
my good thing and bad thing,
I got a couple questions.
When Petro died, did they call
the coroner or a vet?
Yeah, and on his tombstone,
are they gonna put his age
in dog years or human years?
I think I know a couple
of robots
that aren'’t getting ram chips
tonight, if you Don'’t--
ram chips?
- Oh!
- Uh-oh.
Well, uh, I thought
it was a great film.
It was, uh,
the feel-good film of 1938,
or whenever the heck
it was made.
Yeah, i'’d give it two thumbs up,
if I had thumbs.
You had thumbs for a minute,
pal. What'’d you do with them?
You stuck '’em into
my access ports, didn'’t you?
Excuse me, those were my
access ports and my thumbs.
Listen, if you guys
keep arguing,
you'’re not
gonna get anything.
I'’ll take '’em all,
give '’em to gypsy.
[Gasping]
Hey, that'’s not fair.
She wasn'’t even in the--
in the experiment this week.
Well, that'’s why I created
a peripheral character--
so you two could work out
your free will, all right?
I thought we weren'’t
gonna delve into ontological
discourse this week.
Well, what would you
rather have happen?
- I could turn gypsy off.
- [Gasping]
And then you could just live
the rest of your lives
as pan-dimensional beings.
Would you like that?
Oh, thus spoke zarathustra.
You know, who made you
Uber-man this week?
Uh, sirs, I think that'’s the end
of the experiment this week.
Uh, I hope you'’re pleased.
Of course
we'’re not pleased.
Can'’t you see a mad scientist
has just died?
Yeah, what'’s wrong with you?
I hope you and your little
existential pals
have fun this week.
Here, file this.
[Groaning]
♪♪